Tufts Family Collection MS050
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts Family Collection
1930 -- 1980
circa 0253 -- 0350, 1791 -- 2013
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts, Charles
MS050
7.5 Linear Feet 8 boxes and 2 portraits
This collection contains materials relating to the Tufts family and consists of business and legal records; clippings; correspondence; genealogical materials such as family trees, family histories, and a family Bible; photographs and portraits; publications; scrapbooks; subject files; and the Tufts Kinsmen newsletter. The bulk of this material dates from 1930 to 1980, with the business ledgers and many of the legal documents dating from 1791 to about 1920.
Biographical / Historical
Charles Tufts (1781-1876) donated the land on which Tufts College was founded in 1852. He was the son of Daniel and Abigail Tufts (also a Tufts descendent) and a direct descendent of Peter Tufts, an early colonist who settled in Malden in 1638.
Charles Tufts, a member of the First Universalist Church in Charlestown, donated the land on which the Universalist college, Tufts College, was founded in 1852. His donation of twenty acres was then valued at $20,000 and was located on one of the highest hills in the Boston area, called Walnut Hill (originally Walnut Tree Hill). The land was given to the Universalist Church on the condition that it be used for a college. With subsequent gifts and his estate, his donations of land to the college totaled more than 100 acres.
Charles Tufts was born on the north side of Broadway opposite the Powder House in Somerville (originally part of Charlestown, then Medford, now Somerville). Daniel Tufts (1753-1838), Charles's father, was the son of Nathaniel Tufts (1724-1771), who in turn was son of Peter Tufts (1697-1776), the third son of John Tufts (1665-1728). Daniel was a farmer and brickmaker and possibly engaged in slaughtering and tanning. Charles Tufts also worked in farming and brick manufacturing. He eventually owned substantial amounts of land in Medford and Somerville. He married Hannah Robinson (1795-1873) in 1821; the two had no children. Upon his marriage in 1821, Charles and Hannah Tufts moved to a house which they built at 141 Washington Street in Somerville. Now razed, the stones from the front steps of the house were moved to the campus and as of 1999 are located along the pathway leading from Professors Row to Tisch Library.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 4 series: Portraits; Genealogical materials; Legal and financial records; and Subject files.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Jay F. Tufts research files were donated in several shipments from 1981 – 1983. Subject files were previously transferred to this collection from the Vertical File Collection (UA073). Issues of the Tufts Kinsmen were collected via subscription. The majority of the legal and financial records were purchased by Tufts University from The Manuscripts Company of Springfield, Virginia in 1978.
Related Materials
Artifact Collection, circa 500 BC -- 1980. Tufts University. Digital Collections and Archives. Medford, MA.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains materials relating to the Tufts family and consists of business and legal records; clippings; correspondence; genealogical materials such as family trees, family histories, and a family Bible; photographs and portraits; publications; slides; scrapbooks; subject files; and the Tufts Kinsmen newsletter. The bulk of this material dates from 1930 to 1980, with the business ledgers and many of the legal documents dating from 1791 to about 1920.
The majority of the collection consists of research files compiled by Jay F. Tufts in the course of research for his self-published book Tufts Family History (1963). These files consist of correspondence discussing the history and genealogy of various branches of the Tufts family, mainly focusing on the descendants of Peter Tufts, who came to Massachusetts from England in the 1600s. Genealogical materials also include the Tufts Kinsmen Newsletters, an approximately 10-page newsletter published quarterly by the Tufts Kinsmen Association from circa 1974 to circa 1992 relating Tufts family stories, histories, and genealogies.
Legal and financial records include ledgers and account books and mainly pertain to the Tufts family brickworks and tannery in Charlestown (now Somerville), Massachusetts, dating from 1797 – 1860. Subject files contain correspondence, clippings, and photographs relating to Tuft family members who were alumni, faculty, staff, or honorary degree recipients.
Jay Franklin Tufts (1885 -- 1984)
Jay Franklin Tufts (1885 – 1984) was the son of John William Tufts (1854 – 1935) and Emma Florence Tufts (1856 – 1943). He was born in Maineville, Ohio and married Ora Lind Anderson of Conneaut, Ohio on July 8th 1912. Jay Tufts opened a jewelry store with his father in Loveland, Ohio and had one child, Jane Elizabeth Tufts. In 1963 Tufts self-published Tufts Family History: a true account and history of our Tufts families – from and before – 1638-1963. He donated the source materials for the book to Tufts in several shipments from 1981 to 1983. He died in Cleveland, Ohio, in 1984.
Herbert Freedman Adams (1924 -- 2003)
Herbert Freedman Adams (1924 – 2003) was a New England genealogist who founded the Tufts Kinsmen Association, a group of people interested in Tufts heritage. He was born in Massachusetts in 1924 and was a skilled mechanic/repairman before entering the US Army as a private in 1943 where he served in the Engineer Corp. After leaving the military in 1946, he became a professional tax assessor and in 1953, Adams began specializing in land research for property surveys. Related to the Tufts family by marriage, and an amateur genealogist, Adams published The Compendium of Tufts Kinsmen: a substitutive genealogy in 1975 and Adams of Massachusetts: Herbert Freeman Adams collection in 1983. He founded the Tufts Kinsmen Association in 1974. The Association published a quarterly newsletter titled The Tufts Kinsmen. Tufts Kinsmen Association in the mid-1980s. A revised version of his first book was published in 2010 as Tufts Kinsmen. He died in 2003 and is buried in Mount Hope Cemetery in Mattapan, MA.
University history; Genealogy; Medford/Somerville history; Tufts Family
- Portraits, circa 1852 -- 1876; MS050.001; 2 Artifact(s)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains portraits of Charles Tufts, donor of the land on which Tufts College was founded in 1852, and his wife, Hannah Tufts.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Tufts, Hannah, circa 1852; MS050.001.001.00001
  - Tufts, Charles, circa 1876; MS050.001.001.00002
    Inscription below portrait reads "One of the original members of this parish. He gave the land upon which this building stands."
- Genealogical materials, circa 253 -- 350, 1817 -- 1992; MS050.002; 6.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains genealogical materials including clippings, correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks, the Tufts Kinsmen newsletters, and legal documents such as marriage licenses, deeds, and wills. The bulk of this material dated from 1953 to 1992.
  The majority of this series consists of materials compiled by Jay F. Tufts as research for his book Tufts Family History: a true account and history of our Tufts families – from and before – 1638-1963, self-published in 1963. These files contain correspondence discussing the history and genealogy of various branches of the Tufts family, mainly focusing on the descendants of a Peter Tufts, who came to Massachusetts from England in the 1600s. Some of the correspondents also sent Jay F. Tufts family photographs, clippings, publications by and about family members, and family records, included here.
  The series also includes the Tufts Kinsmen newsletters, an approximately 10-page newsletter published quarterly by the Tufts Kinsmen Association from circa 1974 to circa 1992 relating Tufts family stories, histories, and genealogies. The Tufts Kinsmen Association was founded by Herbert F. Adams, a Tufts relative by marriage in 1974. Kinsmen materials include some correspondence and photographs along with the publications.
  There is also a Tufts family Bible (1843) belonging to Susan Adams Tufts.
  This series is arranged into 2 sub-series: Jay F. Tufts research files and Tufts Kinsmen. This series also contains a Tufts family Bible.
  - Jay F. Tufts research files, circa 0253 -- 0350, 1817 -- 1982; MS050.002.001
    This sub-series contains Jay F. Tufts's research files, which consist of materials he collected on the Tufts family while writing his book Tufts Family History: a true account and history of our Tufts families – from and before – 1638-1963, (self-published,1963). These files consist largely of correspondence discussing family history and genealogy of various branches of the Tufts family, mainly focusing on the descendants of Peter Tufts (1617-1700), an English immigrant to Massachusetts.
    Family members and other correspondents enclosed many Tufts-related items along with their letters, including photographs, clippings, scrapbooks, music scores, and publications. Photographic formats include daguerreotypes, tintypes, slides, negatives, and cartes-de-visite. They also sent old family documents, including correspondence dating back to the early 1800s, wills, deeds, and marriage certificates. Occasionally they included something even more unusual: this sub-series also contains several artifacts such as a box of Roman brick and tile pieces sent by Jack Elsden Tuffs from England, and a copper printing plate.
    This series was maintained in received order.
    - Correspondence, 1908 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, William - correspondence, 1961; MS050.002.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
    - Vaughan, Grace Tufts - correspondence, 1955; MS050.002.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
    - Clippings and postcards, 1922 -- 1950; MS050.002.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Jay and Ora Tufts - correspondence, circa 1981; MS050.002.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
    - Moyer, Geraldine H. Tufts - correspondence, 1958 -- 1982; MS050.002.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
    - Harris, Maude Tufts, 1954 -- 1967; MS050.002.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Norman R. - clippings, circa 1977; MS050.002.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Charles; Hannah Tufts; and Tufts University - correspondence and photographs, circa 1964; MS050.002.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, John Wheeler - correspondence, 1956 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Moses - correspondence, 1955; MS050.002.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
    - Albach, Clara Tufts - correspondence, 1956 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
    - Tufts Library, 1954 -- 1982; MS050.002.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Nathan - correspondence, 1945 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
    - Barry, Ellsworth A. - correspondence, 1954; MS050.002.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
    - Pierce, Doris Edith Whittier - correspondence, 1960 -- 1970; MS050.002.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Lenk M. - correspondence, 1954 -- 1972; MS050.002.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Nathaniel - correspondence, 1951 -- 1982; MS050.002.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Oliver A. - correspondence, 1953 -- 1973; MS050.002.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Warren Ward and Emma Viola Tufts - correspondence, 1954 --1971; MS050.002.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Clinton R. - correspondence, 1949 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Carl M. - correspondence, 1952 -- 1956; MS050.002.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Everett G. - correspondence, 1966 -- 1967; MS050.002.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Richard G. and Kathy Glading Tufts - correspondence, 1966 -- 1969; MS050.002.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
    - Gilliam, Nina Coleman - correspondence, 1950 -- 1970; MS050.002.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
    - Gunnell-Haws, Ester (Kimbler) - correspondence, 1953 -- 1967; MS050.002.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
    - Cobb, Rosalie Margaret Karapetoff - Who's Who certificate and photographs, circa 1962 -- 1976; MS050.002.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
    - Cobb, Rosalie Margaret Karapetoff - correspondence and photographs, 1936 -- 1968; MS050.002.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Ella Mae Pentz - correspondence and genealogies, 1958 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
    - Greeley, Hopkinson, Huffman, and Kirkland families - correspondence, 1962 -- 1974; MS050.002.001.001.00030 (Box 1)
    - Canada research - correspondence, 1955; MS050.002.001.001.00031 (Box 1)
    - Larson, Marie Harriet (Tufts) - correspondence, 1959 -- 1978; MS050.002.001.001.00032 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Francis - clippings and genealogies, circa 1950's -- 1960's; MS050.002.001.001.00033 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Harford D. - correspondence, 1963; MS050.002.001.001.00034 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Thomas W. - correspondence, 1966; MS050.002.001.001.00035 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Webster - correspondence, 1962 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.001.00036 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Sharon Lee - correspondence and clippings, 1962; MS050.002.001.001.00037 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Walter Lawrence - correspondence, 1964; MS050.002.001.001.00038 (Box 1)
    - Sokup, Dorothy Tufts - correspondence, 1959; MS050.002.001.001.00039 (Box 1)
    - Van Vechten, Cortland C. and Mary Josephine Thompson Van Vechten - correspondence, 1960 -- 1961; MS050.002.001.001.00040 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Edith Souther - correspondence, 1935 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.001.00041 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Roy C., Harold Leon Tufts, the Case family, and the Tyler family - correspondence, 1956 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.001.00042 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, James Hayden - correspondence, 1942 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.001.00043 (Box 1)
    - Ireland research - correspondence, 1955 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.001.00044 (Box 1)
    - Taylor, Christine Tufts - correspondence, 1954 -- 195; MS050.002.001.001.00045 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Henry - correspondence, 1953 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.001.00046 (Box 1)
    - Jones, William Preble - correspondence, clippings, and publications, 1930 -- 1958; MS050.002.001.001.00047; 2 Folder(s) (Box 1)
    - Greenwood, Mary C. Tufts - correspondence and genealogies, 1960 -- 1969; MS050.002.001.001.00048 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Elmer Emmons - correspondence, 1954 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.001.00049 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence and genealogies, 1951 -- 1974; MS050.002.001.001.00050 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Ina Whitney - correspondence, 1954 -- 1981; MS050.002.001.001.00051 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Robert J., Pam Tufts, and Gladys Tufts Iliff - correspondence, 1965 -- 1972; MS050.002.001.001.00052 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Alvin Vinton - correspondence, 1956 -- 1965; MS050.002.001.001.00053 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Raymond H. - correspondence, 1964 -- 1976; MS050.002.001.001.00054 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, Robert D. and Amy Tufts - correspondence, 1960 -- 1973; MS050.002.001.001.00055 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, John Marshall - correspondence, 1955 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.001.00056 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, James Gordon - correspondence, 1954 -- 1953; MS050.002.001.001.00057 (Box 1)
    - Makepeace, Jennie Howes - correspondence and clippings, 1954 -- 1961; MS050.002.001.001.00058 (Box 1)
    - Tufts, James Keltie - correspondence, 1954 -- 1975; MS050.002.001.001.00059 (Box 1)
    - Haws, Esther Kimbler Gunnell - correspondence and Mormon Bible, circa 1950 -- 1958; MS050.002.001.001.00060 (Box 1)
    - Jackson field hockey team - photographs, circa 1924; MS050.002.001.001.00061 (Box 1)
    - James Tufts: a Memorial - publication, 1902; MS050.002.001.001.00062 (Box 1)
    - Greer, Ellen Matilda Watson - correspondence, circa 1954 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.001.00063 (Box 1)
    - Beck, Rhean L. M. - correspondence, 1955 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.001.00064 (Box 1)
    - Smith, Lilla May Tufts - photographs, circa 1870 -- 1910; MS050.002.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Elmer L. - correspondence, 1954 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
    - Quint, May Parker Tufts - correspondence and family trees, circa 1968 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
    - Diebel, Frederick D. - correspondence, 1957 -- 1981; MS050.002.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
    - King, Erman and Therese King - photographs, circa 1955 -- 1956; MS050.002.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
    - Kingeta, Noreen Tufts - correspondence, circa 1957; MS050.002.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Robie Wilfred - correspondence and clippings, 1839 -- 1982; MS050.002.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
    - Coleman, Julia Bishod - correspondence, 1905 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
    - Valder, Charles B. and Julia Valder - correspondence and genealogies, 1971 -- 1975; MS050.002.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
    - Smith, Lilla Tufts - correspondence, circa 1846 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
    - Lockstone, Agneline (Brown) - correspondence, 1957 -- 1978; MS050.002.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
    - Wiseman, Warren P. and wife, circa 1976; MS050.002.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
    - Maineville Ohio Tufts families - genealogies and publication, 1950 -- 1982; MS050.002.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Stephen - genealogies, circa 1950's; MS050.002.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
    - Vidito, Ila Jane Tufts - correspondence, 1955 -- 1966; MS050.002.001.002.00015 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Primruse - correspondence, 1956; MS050.002.001.002.00016 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Cecil Leo - correspondence, 1954 -- 1956; MS050.002.001.002.00017 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Gordon R. - correspondence, 1955 -- 1956; MS050.002.001.002.00018 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Horton - correspondence, 1956 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.002.00019 (Box 2)
    - Morrell, Maude Tufts - correspondence, 1956; MS050.002.001.002.00020 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Robert Rider - correspondence and clippings, 1956 -- 1967; MS050.002.001.002.00021 (Box 2)
    - Robinson, Beverly and Winnifred Corwin - correspondence and photographs, 1960 -- 1982; MS050.002.001.002.00022 (Box 2)
    - Savary, Ola M. Tufts - correspondence and photographs, circa 1945 -- 1956; MS050.002.001.002.00023 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Irvin L. - correspondence, 1963; MS050.002.001.002.00024 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Gordon Willoughby - correspondence, 1955 -- 1956; MS050.002.001.002.00025 (Box 2)
    - Linton, Dorothy Tufts - correspondence, 1965 -- 1966; MS050.002.001.002.00026 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Robert James - correspondence, 1956 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.002.00027 (Box 2)
    - Nichol, Janet Tufts - correspondence, 1957 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.002.00028 (Box 2)
    - Holmes, Susan P. (Tufts) - correspondence, 1964; MS050.002.001.002.00029 (Box 2)
    - Wellman Family - records and correspondence, circa 1870 -- 1973; MS050.002.001.002.00030 (Box 2)
    - Gover, Mildred Potter Lowe - correspondence, 1961 -- 1972; MS050.002.001.002.00031 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Harris K. - correspondence, 1953 -- 1968; MS050.002.001.002.00032 (Box 2)
    - Kerr, Lura A. Tufts - correspondence, 1961 -- 1980; MS050.002.001.002.00033 (Box 2)
    - Harris, Ruth G. Tufts and Paul D. Harris - correspondence, 1954 -- 1969; MS050.002.001.002.00034 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Verney R. and Ella Jane (Crum) Tufts - correspondence, 1964; MS050.002.001.002.00035 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Robert G. - correspondence, 1955 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.002.00036 (Box 2)
    - Kennedy, Cora Tufts - correspondence, 1962 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.002.00037 (Box 2)
    - Willoughby, Vivian Kimbler - correspondence, circa 1957 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.002.00038 (Box 2)
    - Wilson, Gladys W. - correspondence, 1955 -- 1966; MS050.002.001.002.00039 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Arthur M. - correspondence, 1961; MS050.002.001.002.00040 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Edward Allison - correspondence, 1965; MS050.002.001.002.00041 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Servetus - genealogies, circa 1982; MS050.002.001.002.00042 (Box 2)
    - Weise, Katherine Tufts - correspondence, 1961 -- 1965; MS050.002.001.002.00043 (Box 2)
    - Sanson, Leslie and Katherine B. Sanson - correspondence, 1965; MS050.002.001.002.00044 (Box 2)
    - Richardson, Grace Tufts - correspondence, 1960 -- 1961; MS050.002.001.002.00045 (Box 2)
    - Pratt, Marsha Whitney - correspondence and publication, 1964 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.002.00046 (Box 2)
    - Morrison, Florence G. - correspondence and clippings, 1953 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.002.00047 (Box 2)
    - Peters, Margaret - correspondence, clippings, and photographs, circa 1957 -- 1975; MS050.002.001.002.00048 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Ware Gilbert - correspondence, 1956 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.002.00049 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, William Oscar and Nancy Poor Tufts - correspondence, circa 1940 -- 1967; MS050.002.001.002.00050 (Box 2)
    - Shaffer, Audrey Graham - correspondence, 1966 -- 1973; MS050.002.001.002.00051 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Grace Gibson and William R. Tufts - correspondence, 1963 -- 1973; MS050.002.001.002.00052 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Marie V. (Smith) - correspondence, circa 1954 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.002.00053 (Box 2)
    - Lovejoy, Fredrick C. - correspondence, 1954 -- 1973; MS050.002.001.002.00054 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, George Lewis - genealogies, circa 1982; MS050.002.001.002.00055 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, James Walker and Richard S. Tufts - correspondence and clippings, 1946 -- 1967; MS050.002.001.002.00056 (Box 2)
    - Richardson, David R. - correspondence, 1974; MS050.002.001.002.00057 (Box 2)
    - Mulford, Mary Elsie and Charles Dudley Mulford - correspondence, 1953 -- 1963; MS050.002.001.002.00058 (Box 2)
    - The Adams Papers: Part III - clippings and correspondence, 1962; MS050.002.001.002.00059 (Box 2)
    - Tufft, Tufte, Tuff, and Tofts families - correspondence, 1954 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.002.00060 (Box 2)
    - Storer, Ella Mae Tufts - correspondence, 1954 -- 1955; MS050.002.001.002.00061 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Susan Browning Cotton - correspondence, 1954 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.002.00062 (Box 2)
    - Quinn, Joe - correspondence, 1965 -- 1967; MS050.002.001.002.00063 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Charles and Josephine Frances Tufts - correspondence and clippings, 1964 -- 1980; MS050.002.001.002.00064 (Box 2)
    - The Peter Tufts House - correspondence, circa 1932 -- 1956; MS050.002.001.002.00065 (Box 2)
    - Anderson, Glen Williams and Frank W. Anderson - correspondence, 1960 -- 1973; MS050.002.001.002.00066 (Box 2)
    - Greenwood, May C. and Mercer J. Greenwood - correspondence, 1957 -- 1973; MS050.002.001.002.00067 (Box 2)
    - Robin, Kathrin Marie Tufts - correspondence, 1966; MS050.002.001.002.00068 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Benjamin Francis and Isabella Hill Tufts - clippings, circa 1977; MS050.002.001.002.00069 (Box 2)
    - Tufts, Ella Mae and Clyde E. Storer - genealogies, circa 1965; MS050.002.001.002.00070 (Box 2)
    - Fairbanks, Cleon J. - Correspondence and genealogies, circa 1960 -- 1963; MS050.002.001.002.00071 (Box 2)
    - Fonda, Elizabeth E. - correspondence, circa 1959; MS050.002.001.002.00072 (Box 2)
    - Williams, Irvin - correspondence, 1956 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Mitchell Moses and Lucinda McCormick Tufts - correspondence, circa 1955 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Seth Greely - genealogies, circa 1982; MS050.002.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, John Marshall - correspondence, 1970 -- 1972; MS050.002.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Walter IV - correspondence, 1956; MS050.002.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
    - Lane, Shirley Tufts - correspondence, 1968 -- 1974; MS050.002.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
    - Guy, Nettie Mae Tufts - correspondence, 1956 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
    - Howard, Ada Gertrude Tufts - correspondence, 1959 -- 1961; MS050.002.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
    - Knowlton, Evelyn F. Littlefield - correspondence, circa 1965 -- 1972; MS050.002.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Lina May Day - correspondence, 1954 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.003.00010 (Box 3)